要命
Oh, boy.
又到了牲口拍賣季的第一天了嗎
Is it already the first day of livestock auction season again?
每年都是同一天啊 米奇爾
It's the same day every year, Mitchell --
第一顆番茄成熟后的第十五天
a fortnight after the first ripe tomato comes in.
而且說真的
And seriously?
現在的拍賣叫價都這么業余了嗎
This is what passes for auction-calling these days?
你會不會太嚴苛了一點
Is it possible you're being a tad harsh?
當你曾經是某個領域的頂尖人物
You know, when you've been at the top of your field --
大巴格縣拍賣叫價冠軍
Greater Bug County Auction-Calling Champ
還連續贏了三年
three years running --
那你眼里就只能看到缺點和不足
it's hard to see anything but the inadequacies.
所以巴瑞辛尼科夫才沒法觀看其他舞蹈
It's why Baryshnikov couldn't watch others dance.
什么 他明明擔任過藝術總監...
What? He was the Artistic Director of --
你都在這房子里住了多久了
How long have you lived in this house?!
最后你會發現是一頭叫巴瑞辛尼科夫的豬
It's gonna wind up being some pig named Baryshnikov
或叫其他鬼名字的
or some damn thing.
你的小號課上得怎么樣了
So, how was your trumpet lesson?
太美妙了
It was amazing. Yeah.
那些課程[療程]真的改變了我的人生
Oh, these sessions just have really changed my life.
嚴格來說 我沒說謊
Technically, uh, not a lie.
我從兩年前開始上小號課
Uh, I started taking trumpet lessons two years ago.
但之后我發現隔壁店的按摩
But then I noticed the place next door
跟課程同樣價格 于是...
was offering massages for the same price, so...
你懂的
you know.
我很內疚 自己去放松 而小卡...
And I felt bad relaxing while Cam was...
一個人照顧莉莉
solo-parenting Lily.
但話說回來 我倆都是跟一個
But -- But we were both spending time
亞洲女性共處 讓她踩背[羞辱]
with an Asian woman who walked all over us.
你每次從那里回來
You always smell like lavender
身上都有薰衣草的味道
when you come back from that place.
那個是 是閥鍵油
Uh, yeah, it's the -- it's the valve oil
上在...你知道
for the, um -- you know,
就是上在... 小號的按鍵里
the t-- the tooting buttons.
我們該盡快出發了
We should probably, uh, hit the road soon.
一小時后就要舉行高中畢業典禮了
High school graduation's in an hour.
好丟臉啊
It's so humiliating
以副校長身份出席這種活動
being the Vice Principal at these things.
這只是象征性的地位
It's just a ceremonial position
其實我只是坐在布朗校長身后
where you have to sit behind Principal Brown,
禮貌地鼓掌
politely clapping
眼看他設定歷史的進程
while he gets to set the course of history.
不過我爸要在畢業典禮上致辭
Well, it could be fun with my dad giving
應該會很有意思
the commencement address, though.
我偷瞄了他的備忘卡
I got a peek at his note cards,
我不想劇透里面的內容
and I don't want to give anything away,
但是那個頭上涂滿發蠟
but the young kid who boarded the bus
手提著紙板行李箱
with the hair full of Brylcreem
懷揣著夢想登上大巴的年輕孩子
and a cardboard suitcase full of dreams --
是他
it was him.
我得接一下電話 是地方教育局長皮爾斯
Oh, I have to take this. It's Superintendent Pierce.
您好 先生 真榮幸 請問有什么事
Hello, good sir. To what do I owe this honor?
不會吧
Oh, no.
太可怕了
That's horrible.
布朗校長出車禍啦
Principal Brown got into a car accident!
也就是說 作為第二順位的校領導
W-Which means, as next in the line of succession,
我可以主持今天的畢業典禮
I get to preside over today's graduation.
這就是為什么高級行政官員
You know, this is why senior administration officials
從來不一起出行
never travel together.
別人倒霉你卻幸災樂禍 我本該覺得不好
Your glee at another man's misfortune should trouble me,
但你這副樣子又有點性感
but there's also something sort of sexy about it.
權力就是春藥
Well, power is an aphrodisiac.
或許晚點你可以扮演校長
Maybe later you could be the principal
而我扮演還差了幾個學分的學生
and I could be the student who's a few credits short.
我不乖
Hmm. A bad, bad boy
需要被好好調教
who needs to be taught right from wrong.
因為我成長于一個破碎家庭
'Cause I grew up in a broken home,
社工常來我家 父母總為錢爭吵
where social workers and constant fights about money
所以...
were just --
算了 這編到我開始感覺難受了
Okay, well, now I'm just sad.
我們能換位子嗎
Can we switch seats?
我剛好坐在通風口下面
I'm right under a vent.
這對我的喉嚨不好
This is not good for my instrument.
你這么認真對待這次致辭 真好啊
Oh, so nice that you're taking this speech so seriously.
你當年為米奇和小卡的婚禮祝酒時
When you did Mitch and Cam's wedding toast,
嘴里還塞滿了腰果呢
you had your mouth full of cashews.
注意看你弟弟啊
Hey, pay attention to your brother.
是你讓他開始練空手道的
You got him into karate.
我不是故意的
Not on purpose.
我只是給他看了幾部《粉紅豹》的卡通電影
I just showed him a few "Pink Panther" movies.
喬
Joe?
我不想再玩
I-I-I don't want to play
妙探長克魯索和卡托的游戲了
this Inspector Clouseau and Cato game anymore.
我可不是害怕哦
It's not that I'm scared.
我只是 有點忙
It's just, I-I'm a little busy --
他就是個小變態[《驚魂記》]
He's a little psycho.
對了 千萬別給他看這部電影
Which we must never show him, by the way.
如果我看起來心神不寧 抱歉
And sorry if I'm distracted.
今天是加州藝術學院的裁生日
It's cut day at CalArts.
我有一半同學都沒被叫回去繼續讀
Half of the class isn't being asked back.
曼尼 母親的直覺告訴我
Manny, my mother's intuition
你沒什么好擔心的
tells me that you have nothing to worry about.
真的太殘酷了
It's just so cruel.
我還有一半課程就能拿到劇本創作學位
I'm halfway to a playwriting degree
難道他們要就這樣把我趕去街頭嗎
and they're just gonna throw me out on the street
我都沒法養活自己
with no way to support myself?
正如一個睿智的男人在兩小時后要說的那樣
As a wise man will say in about two hours --
"生活把石頭滾到你的道路前 你要心懷感激
"Be grateful for the rocks life rolls in your path,
因為有一天 你會視它們為墊腳石"
for one day, you'll see them as stepping stones."
這句是從"可能要用"那堆里拿來的
I had that in my "maybe" pile.
相信自己啊 杰
Trust yourself, Jay.
老天 是學校發來的郵件
Oh, God. It's an e-mail from school.
我可沒法在眾人面前看這郵件
I don't think I can read this in front of people.
加油 喬
Let's go, Joe!
我成功了
I did it!
我成功了 好棒
I did it! Yes!
我媽是不是收買了羅恩老師
Did my mom bribe Sensei Ron?
我就知道你能做到 喬
I knew you could do it, Joe!
母親的直覺告訴我
My mother's intuition told me
你沒什么好擔心的
that you had nothing to worry about.
如果她收買了羅恩老師 那她還收買了誰呢
And if she bribed Sensei Ron, who else did she bribe?
這個獎杯也是我應得的嗎
Did I even deserve this?
你還記得逛超市很無聊的時候嗎
Do you remember when grocery shopping was boring?
不記得
I really don't.
身為家長 很少有機會獲得
As a parent, you don't get
美妙 磊落 沒愧疚感的勝利
a lot of good, clean, guilt-free victories.
所以我們今天
That's why it's hard not to feel
很難不感到自信滿滿
pretty damn good about ourselves today.
因為今天下午
Because this afternoon,
我們要看咱家女兒艾麗克斯畢業
we are going to watch our daughter Alex graduate...
是以優異成績哦
With honors!
從世界知名的加州理工大學
...from the world-renowned Caltech.
? 當你對陣加州理工海貍隊時 ?
♪ When the Caltech Beavers face you at sports ♪
? 準備好讓出手里的球吧 ?
♪ Prepare to relinquish the ba-a-all ♪
他們雖然聰明 但沒把心思放在寫隊歌上
Their best minds weren't focused on the fight song.
沒錯
Yeah.
我沒辦法停止微笑
I just can't stop smiling
一看到艾麗克斯這張穿戴著方帽和長袍的照片
at this picture of Alex in her cap and gown.
真是不敢相信 我跟你的孩子
It's so surreal that one of our kids
居然能獲得如此高的成就
could do something so amazing.
我也愛你們兩個哦
I love you both.
你們倆去拿香檳和鮮花送給艾麗克斯
So, you two, grab champagne and flowers for Alex.
我們...我們去拿雪茄送給杰
We'll, uh -- We'll get some cigars to give to Jay.
行
Yeah.
天啊
Oh, my God.
是斯基普·伍斯南 他炒掉你之后你見過他嗎
It's Skip Woosnam. Have you seen him since he fired you?
見過一次 在賣房會上
Once, at a listing.
我試圖假扮成我自己的3D紙板
I tried to pretend I was a 3D cutout of myself
避免跟他說話
to avoid talking to him.
不過今天我倒想跟他聊聊
But you know what? Today I want to talk to him.
我想我要告訴老斯基普
I think I'll let ol' Skip know
我女兒要從加州理工畢業了
I have a daughter graduating from Caltech.
不 親愛的 我們不是那種
No, honey, we are not the kind of parents
靠炫耀孩子來給自己長臉的家長
who make ourselves look good by bragging about our kids.
那我們為什么要生孩子 克萊爾
Then why did we even have them, Claire?
我們連自鳴得意一下都不行嗎
Are we really not gonna crow about it
我們終于有個孩子做了能讓我們驕傲的事
when one of our kids finally does something we can be proud of?
我好愛你們兩個
I love you both very much.
我不介意做帥氣性感的那個孩子
I'm comfortable being the hot one.
這個月又創紀錄了
Another record month?
謝謝
Well, thank you!
你是世界上最優秀的管家
You're the greatest butler on Earth.
我得掛了
I gotta run.
-菲爾 -斯基普
- Phil? - Skip!
你這家伙 最近好嗎
You son of a gun. How the hell are you?
很好 很好 生意比以往更紅火
Great, great. Business is better than ever.
你怎么樣
How about you?
你現在買真的人形立牌了嗎
Did you, uh, finally get real cutouts?
我不知道你在說什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
我的立牌都是3D高仿真的
Mine are so realistic and 3D,
你肯定像白癡一樣對著它笑來著
you must have been laughing at one of them like an idiot.
我們購物時撞見彼此真是太巧了
How crazy is it we ran into each other shopping, huh?
對了 你的孩子們還好嗎
Say, how are your kids?
都特別好
Terrific. Yeah.
瓊剛找到份康泰納連鎖店的工作
June just, uh, took a job at the Container Store.
真厲害 我也有個孩子
Impressive. I have a kid
對太空特別感興趣
that's interested in space, as well. Yeah.
其實她在考慮去太空總署工作
Considering a job at, uh -- at NASA, actually.
是啊 他看起來很有這方面天賦
Yeah, he, uh, looks like he's got the right stuff.
不 我說的是我女兒
No, I -- it's -- I was talking about my daughter.
爸 你猜怎么著
Oh. Hey, Dad. Dad, guess what.
我一拿起酒瓶雙胞胎就開始亂踢
The twins started kicking the second I picked up booze.
絕對是我的孩子 對吧
They're my kids, right?
我的另一個女兒
My other daughter.
那好 我的演講里
Okay, I'm doing a little thing about
會稍微說說追隨夢想
following your dreams in mine.
你的演講里有嗎
Do you have anything like that in yours?
我的是"追隨熱情"
I say "Follow your passions."
好的 不算重復
Okay, yeah. That's different enough.
好吧
Okay.
那邊有點可疑
Something fishy's going on over here.
我去旁敲側擊一下 看看能查出什么
I'm gonna go shake some trees, see what falls.
你今天真精神 副校長塔克
Looking lovely today, Vice Principal Tucker.
別裝純良少年了 平托斯基
Cut the choirboy act, Pitkowski.
你不喜歡我用這種方式對你說話嗎
Oh, you don't like the way I'm talking to you?
你能跟誰投訴去
Well, who are you gonna complain to?
沒人
No one!
因為我是代理校長
Because I'm the acting principal,
執掌無上大權
clothed in immense power!
等等 這是什么 休想
Wait, what is -- Nope!
我彎腰速度更快
I bend faster.
"杰·普里契特 貓頭鷹殺手"
"Jay Pritchett, Owl Killer"?!
這是什么鬼東西
What the hell is this?
那是1972年
The year was 1972.
我接到了超級大單
I landed a whale --
一艘嘉年華游輪上的所有衣柜
every closet on a Carnival Cruise ship.
為了預算和工期合得上
To make the numbers work,
我需要快速搞到一大批廉價雪松木
I needed a lot of cedar fast and cheap.
結果我砍伐的一片森林
I ended up cutting down a forest
剛好是金斑貓頭鷹最后的棲息地
that happened to be the last habitat of the Golden Speckled Owl.
怎么沒人提我這一舉救下了多少老鼠
You know, nobody talks about all the mice I saved.
沒人提
Nope!
只提貓頭鷹
Just the owls.
你們在計劃抗議嗎
Are you all planning some sort of protest?
在我的監管下 休想
Well, that ain't happening on my watch.
快去坐好
Now go take your seats!
"貓頭鷹希特勒"
"Owl Hitler"?!
這照片是怎么回事 我從沒勒死過貓頭鷹
What the hell is this picture? I never strangled an owl!
讓迪蘭告訴我他人在哪很過分嗎
Is it too much for Dylan to let me know where he is?
我的羊水隨時會破
My water could literally break any minute.
我坐在這沒問題吧
Am I okay sitting here,
還是說像海洋世界前排一樣會被濺濕
or am I in a SeaWorld splash zone situation?
克萊爾 你高中時的死敵艾希莉·沃爾斯
Claire, your old high school nemesis Ashley Walls,
她不是有個女兒嗎
did she have a daughter?
我記得沒有 怎么了
Uh, I don't think so. Why?
那邊那個女人
Well, that woman over there
看起來很像艾希莉 但不太可能
looks just like Ashley, but it can't be.
她看起來只有你一半 美貌
She looks half your... beauty.
艾希莉·沃爾斯
Ashley Walls.
她在每件事上都勝過我
She outdid me at everything.
返校節女王 曲棍球隊長
Homecoming Queen, Field Hockey Captain,
我們上大學前的那個夏天
and the summer before we went away to college,
她竟打敗我成為了普里契特衣柜的實習生
she beat me out for an internship at Pritchett's closets.
克萊爾
Claire?
讓我想想
I...want to say...
艾希莉
Ashley?
-是我 你好嗎 -很好
- Yes! how are you? - Good.
艾希莉·沃爾斯-卡內基
Ashley Walls-Carnegie.
菲利普·漢弗萊·鄧菲
Phillip Humphrey Dunphy.
你最近在忙什么 艾希莉
So, what have you been up to, Ashley?
我是人身傷害律師
Uh, well, I'm a personal injury lawyer.
我有個兄弟靠這個賺了好多錢
I have a buddy that makes bank from that.
他不是律師
He's not a lawyer.
他專門挑豪車碰瓷
He just tries to get nice cars to hit him.
他只是在開玩笑
Yeah, he's just kidding.
我沒開玩笑 媽
No, I'm not, Mom.
-事實上 我 -給 吃塊糖
- In fact, I've ac-- - Here, have a candy.
真無禮
That was rude.
我剛剛遇到了以前的健康教育老師
I just ran into my old health teacher,
她說她一直都覺得
and she said she always expected
我會挺著大肚子參加畢業典禮
to see me pregnant at graduation.
恭喜
Congratulations.
謝謝 是雙胞胎
Oh, thanks. Twins.
抱歉 要是知道他們老爸現在在哪
Sorry, I'd be a lot happier about it
我會開心得多
if I could track their father down.
吃糖
Candy.
看 是你弟弟米奇
Oh, look -- it's your brother, Mitch.
他總是一板一眼的 對不對
Now, he was always a little uptight, wasn't he?
高中時是的 但現在他特別好...
Well, he was in high school, but now he's just the most --
聽好 你今天只有一個任務 小姑娘
Okay, you have one job today, young lady,
支持你大爸
okay, to be supportive.
假如他說了笑話 你就要笑
If your dad makes a joke, you will laugh.
他演講后你怎么做 鼓掌
If he makes a speech, you will what? Applaud.
好吧 我得去找我的座位了
Right. I-I-I'm gonna go find my seat.
但和你敘舊真開心 克萊爾
But it was great catching up with you, Claire.
提一嘴我們女兒今天要從加州理工畢業
No one would blame you if you mentioned you had a daughter
誰也不會責怪你的
graduating from Caltech today.
親愛的 錯過時機了
Honey, the moment has passed.
我得有個好理由才能不經意地過去
I'd need a pretty good reason to just go waltzing over there --
-她的流程單掉了 -太好了
- She dropped her program! - Yes!
克萊爾 你知道我有事會第一個找你商量
Hey, Claire, you know how you're my go-to gal --
-我很忙 -菲爾
- Busy. - Hey, Phil.
你知道我有事會第一個找你商量
You know how you're my go-to guy on stuff?
看來我們戰勝所有不可能成為了摯友
I suppose against all odds, we've become best friends.
是啊
Sure.
很明顯 由我來做畢業演講
So, apparently, some of the students are angry
讓一些學生很生氣
that I'm giving the commencement address.
為什么
Why?
誰知道他們扭曲的腦子是怎么想的
Who knows why their sick minds do anything?
不過我得說 能再次憎恨嬉皮士感覺很好
Gotta say though, it feels good to be hating hippies again.
總之 你能不能幫我巡視一下這地方
Anyway, would you mind giving this place a sweep?
看看有沒有什么可疑的
See if you notice something suspicious.
這就辦好
Consider it done.
你們把什么藏起來了
Hey. What do you got there?
讓我看看你們的袍子下藏著什么
You kids got something under those robes you want to show me?
曼尼 你沒被裁掉
Manny, you passed the cuts,
為什么心情還這么不好
so why aren't you in a better mood?
你賄賂了我的院長讓我通過的 是不是
You bribed my dean to get me past the cut, didn't you?
我永遠不會做那種事
I would never do something like that.
真厲害
Oh, bravo!
假如麗莎·瓦格納有你演技這么好
If Lisa Wagner pulled out that performance,
也許她就不會帶著裝滿手工木偶的卡車
maybe she wouldn't be driving back to her parents' house
和突然迷茫的未來
with a trunk full of handmade puppets
開車回到父母家了
and a suddenly very uncertain future.
我才沒有賄賂誰
I didn't bribe anyone.
我也不知道你怎么會問這種問題
I don't know why you're talking such crazy things.
因為我看見你賄賂羅恩老師了
Because I saw you bribe Sensei Ron.
等等
Wait.
你賄賂羅恩老師了
You bribed Sensei Ron?!
所以這一切都是個謊言
So this is just a lie?!
還有別的誰嗎
Are there others?
我到底算什么人啊
Who the hell even am I?!
我的天
Oh, my God!
想跑可沒門 小朋友
Nice try, kemosabes.
艾希 你節目單掉了
Ash. I think you left your program.
謝謝
Thank you.
想想這些孩子最后
Wow, it's wild to think
光明的前途 真是感慨萬千啊 是吧
where all these kids are gonna end up, right?
我說 有那么多好學校
I mean, there's so many great schools.
其實 我們的
In fact, our --
你還好嗎
Is something wrong?
我們女兒加入恐怖組織了
Our daughter joined ISIS.
美國政府不承認她的公民身份了
The government said she's not an American anymore.
現在我們家門前總是停著一輛貨車
There's a van always parked in front of our house.
天啊 我很難過
Oh, God. I'm so sorry --
克萊爾有沒有說我們的女兒是個天才呀
Did Claire tell you our daughter's a genius?
那么接下來 畢業生們 看看你們的左邊
...and so, graduates, look to your left
再看看右邊
and to your right.
我丟了個小牛仔帽裝飾的簡潔大方的鑰匙鏈
It's a simple key chain with a tiny cowboy hat charm on it.
誰撿到了 請傳上來
If you see it, please pass it forward.
好了 現在有請我們的畢業演講嘉賓
All right, and now on to our commencement speaker.
他是社會的棟梁
He is a pillar of the community,
企業家 行業巨頭 杰·普里契特先生
an entrepreneur and closeteer -- Mr. Jay Pritchett.
畢業典禮
Commencement.
"C"代表著"勇氣"
"C" for "Courage,"
"O"代表著"機遇"
"O" for "Opportunity,"
第一個"M"
the first "M" --
災難來臨了
Disaster had struck.
但是我慌了嗎
But did I panic?
沒有
No.
沒人主動選擇成為戰時的校長
No one chooses to be a wartime principal.
但我們終將被歷史所銘記
But we're the ones history remembers.
二選其一 他們都說
Pick one, they all said --
壁櫥還是百葉窗
closets or blinds.
米奇爾 這要毀了畢業典禮的
Mitchell, he's tanking my graduation.
我打算跳過他 直接進入懷念校友環節
I'm cutting him off and moving right to the in-memoriam section.
那聽起來真是令人"愉快"啊
Well, that would be less depressing.
是是 問題是樂隊的人剛剛走得一個不剩了
Yeah, the problem is, the band just walked out in solidarity.
-給你 -干什么
- Here. - W-What?
米奇爾 紀念儀式不能沒有音樂
Mitchell, you can't have an in memoriam without music.
那太掃興了
That's just a bummer.
拿著
Take it!
你們愛怎么咕咕叫怎么叫 反正我最后成功了
Hoot all you want, but that Brylcreem kid was me!
是的 謝謝你
Yes, hi, thank you.
謝謝你 杰·普里契特 大家鼓掌
Thank you, Jay Pritchett, everyone!
我不知道你們什么感覺 不過我覺得
Wow, I don't know about you, but I feel like
自己視野大開 要走向世界了啊
getting out there and taking on the world, huh?
現在 讓我們銘記
And now, let's remember
今年我們失去的那些友人
those Dolphins we lost this year.
米奇爾 快吹起來 什么都行
Mitchell, play something. Play anything.
吹點特別莊重特別深沉的
Something with the most gravitas.
你知道嗎 我這么一個兩年沒碰過小號的人
You know, for a person who last touched a trumpet two years ago,
吹得還挺好的
I think I sounded pretty good.
吹完了 吹完了
I'm done. I'm done.
好了
All right!
這一年逝去的人真是多啊
That is a lot of deceased for one year.
我們可能要報給警察調查一下了
We should probably have the police check into that.
現在 在授予學位證書之前
And now, before, uh, passing out diplomas,
我想為畢業班的同學
I would like to make sort of a --
致以一些個人的表示
a personal gesture to this graduating class.
當氣球飛向天空 你們會發現每一個
As these balloons fill the sky, know that each one of them
都代表著一個親身鼓舞了我
represents a student who has personally inspired me
讓我對未來充滿美好希望的學生
and filled me with hope for a better tomorrow.
什么情況
What?
代理校長
Acting Principal!
抗議者們黑進了我們的灑水系統
Protesters hacked into our sprinkler system.
五分鐘之后就要啟動了
It's set to go off in five minutes.
我們得推遲畢業典禮
We have to postpone the graduation.
然后錯過我成為校長的機會嗎
And miss my chance of becoming principal?
沒門
Not a chance!
但是沒人能在五分鐘之內念完四百個名字
Well, no one can read 400 names in five minutes.
是嗎
Oh, really?
所有訓練 所有錯過的派對
All that training, all those parties missed,
所有那些參加過的拍賣會
all those auctions attended
都是為了此時此刻
were for this moment right here, right now.
同學們 你們好 當你們聽到你們名字的時候
Students, hi! When you hear your name,
請走上臺來 拿走你們的學位證書
please proceed to the stage and grab your diploma.
奈莉·阿布瑞莎米 艾莉森·阿科斯塔
Nelly Abrishami, Allison Acosta,
弗里達·阿拉法利 斯科特·"討厭鬼"·阿爾巴內塞
Frieda Alafary, Scott "The Skunk" Albanese,
杰西卡·埃倫尼克 理查德·湯普森·艾倫
Jessica Alenick, Richard Thompson Allen,
拉瓦利亞·阿米努 拉里·阿納科恩
Lavaria Aminu, Larry Annecone,
達拉·阿爾勒特 丹尼爾·戴伊·阿倫森
Darla Arleto, Daniel Dey Aronson...
我本來可以念完的
I was gonna make it!
然后
And then...
我遇到了波蘭名字
I hit the Polish names.
切斯沃夫·沃拉德瑞扎克科沃斯基
Czeslaw Wlodaryzack-ck-kowsky.
沃洛迪斯勞·沃勞德
Wladyslaw Wlod...
尼斯基 對
nisky? Yeah.
邁拉·扎林斯基
Myra Zarinsky --
好了 快撤快撤
OK, all right, all right
如果我們離爸爸和小卡遠一點 可能還有機會
Okay, if we steer clear of Dad and Cam, we've got a chance
在這堆暴民動武的時候混進他們人群不被打
of blending into the mob when they turn violent.
這是什么情況
What the hell is this?
是這樣的 顯然 為貓頭鷹抗議的人
Okay, well, apparently, when those owls
黑進灑水系統 是影響全校區的
hacked into the sprinkler system, it was school-wide.
他們不讓任何人進停車場
They're not letting anyone into the parking structure.
不是吧
Oh, no!
我希望這不會讓我們錯過
I hope this doesn't mean we're gonna have to miss
今天的第二個畢業典禮
the second graduation of the day.
運氣真好
How lucky is that?
我正拉著優步訂單 你們就打過電話來了
Me cruising by with an Uber fare right when you called.
-幸運幸運 -真好
- So lucky. Very lucky. - Very good.
你到了 杰拉爾德
Well, this is you, Gerald.
希望今天開始你能
Let's have today be the day
不再是為了你父親演奏
you stop playing for your dad
而是為自己演奏
and start playing for Gerald.
話說 這提醒了我
That -- That kind of reminds me --
對不起 我騙你說自己上了小號課
I'm sorry I lied about the trumpet lessons.
沒事 這才不是我今天最倒霉的部分
Oh, please. Not the worst part of my day.
我現在想明白了布朗校長是故意坑我讓我失敗
I'm realizing now that Principal Brown set me up to fail.
根本沒有什么車禍
There was no car crash,
跟登月一樣都是騙人的
just like there was no moon landing.
-小卡 -太空里旗幟是不會飄揚的 米奇爾
- Cam - Flags can't wave in space, Mitchell.
好了好了 我被羞辱得比你們都過分
Hey, hey, hey, I was humiliated much worse than you.
太不公平了
It was so unfair.
兢兢業業一輩子最后無人贊譽
A lifetime of service out the window.
你們以為我每晚閉上眼睛
You think I don't see the faces of owls
不會看到那些貓頭鷹的臉嗎
every night I close my eyes?
至少你有大家心服口服的成就
At least you've accomplished something they can tear down.
我是個騙子
I'm a fraud!
你看到你對你弟弟做了什么嗎
You see what you did to your brother?
看那難過又受傷的大眼睛
Look at those sad, hurt eyes.
就像難過的小貓頭鷹
Like a sad little owl.
也許要是你相信自己的兒子
Well, maybe if you believed in your sons
而不是跟每個人都來哥倫比亞式握手
instead of giving everyone Colombian handshakes.
什么
What?!
我可從來沒有當著哪個男人家室的面
I've never sanded down a man's fingers
跟他親密握手
in front of his family!
你是說賄賂的事啊
Oh, you mean the bribes?
你沒法否認了
You can't deny it anymore.
看我們院長發出來的照片
Look at this photo on my dean's Instagram.
他戴著的表跟你給羅恩老師的一模一樣
He's wearing the same watch you gave Sensei Ron.
地區教育局長也戴著一樣的表
The superintendent was wearing that same watch.
典禮結束后他跟我握手
I-I noticed it when he shook my hand at the end of the ceremony
他說我"滑天下之大稽"時 我有注意到
and said I was a "Horrifying disgrace."
你賄賂他了嗎
You bribed him?!
是因為這樣我才有資格演說的嗎
Is that how I got my speech?
好了 夠了
Okay, enough!
我相信你們憑自己也能做到
I'm sure you would have gotten all these things on your own,
但世界有時就是那么不公平
but the world sometimes is very unfair!
那些手表只是以防萬一啦
And the watches are like an insurance.
你為什么會有那么多啊
Why do you even have so many?
有時候我吃安眠藥后會夢游網購
Sometimes I do a little bit of Ambien shopping
然后把同樣的東西買一堆
and I buy too much of one thing.
難道你們圣誕節
Didn't you all wonder
收到一樣的有趣襪子時沒想過這事嗎
when you got the same fun socks for Christmas?
-一樣的耶 -我了個去
- Oh, samesies. - I'll be damned!
-我怎么沒收到 -可有趣了
- I don't have those. - They're fun!
對不起 是我不好
I'm sorry, okay?
但我太愛你們了
But I love you guys so much
我不想把你們的愿望交給命運來安排
to leave your dreams to chance.
我想在你長大的故鄉
I suppose where you grew up,
鉆漏洞也是生存的一部分
bending the rules was just a part of life.
你必須得這樣才能活下去
It's what you had to do to get by.
你又怎么會不拿來幫忙你愛的人呢
Why wouldn't you do that to help the people you love?
謝謝你 曼尼
Thank you, Manny.
你謝什么啊 我才不是那么覺得呢
You're not welcome. That's not how I feel.
這是我演出的劇的臺詞
I-It's a speech from a play I was in.
在我說完剛才的臺詞后
Right after that line,
我點事后煙然后重新穿上我的衣服
I light up a cigarette and put my clothes back on.
我是沒事啦 但是...
Yeah, I'm good, but...
我現在不知道我到底是不是憑實力了
now I'll never know if that's why I made the cut.
好了 別這樣 聽我說
Okay, stop. Look.
大家今天都過了很慘的一天
We've all had a terrible day today --
我沒有啊
Not me.
拉的客人都是大單 超贊的瑜伽課
Tons of great fares, amazing yoga class --
我這邊在醞釀一個點呢 兄弟
I-I was building to something, buddy.
但是大家庭有這么一個好處
But that's one of the great things about being in a family.
我們能分享其他人的勝利榮光
We get to share in each other's victories.
而艾麗克斯今天有一場大勝利
And Alex has a huge victory today
能讓我們大家都感覺好受
that can make us all feel better.
所以我們...
So let's...
把這糟糕的一天轉虧為盈 感覺美...
turn around this crap day with a nice, feel-good --
那是艾麗克斯嗎
Hey, is that Alex?
天啊 停車
Oh, my God. Pull over!
停
Back up!
艾麗克斯 親愛的 怎么了 你還好嗎
Alex! Honey, what happened? Are you okay?
今天周幾
What day is it?
無所謂 反正時間根本不會循環
Not that time is anything but a flat circle.
我們課都結束了 期末考也考完了
So...we were done with classes, done with finals,
就跟史上所有大四生一樣
and, like college seniors since the beginning of time,
我們也決定來瘋狂一把
we decided to get a little nuts.
查格[干杯] 查格 查格 查格 查格
Chug! Chug! Chug! Chug! Chug!
我們的同學阿施施·查格
Our classmate Ashish Chug...
成功啦[喝完啦]
I did it!
黑進了我們的出入證
...hacked his key card to get us access
往里面加了進出圖書館限制區域的權限
to the restricted section of the library.
我們決定去讀阿利斯特最后定理
We decided to read Alister's Last Theorem.
哥特羅布·阿利斯特寫出了0=1的證明
Gottlob Alister wrote a proof showing that zero equals 1.
這代表數學是無意義的
This rendered mathematics meaningless
并且害他發了瘋
and drove him insane.
根據傳說 同樣的命運降臨在了
According to legend, the same fate befalls anyone
每一個閱讀并能理解他證明的人身上
who reads and understands the proof.
天啊
Good God.
如果數學沒有意義
If mathematics doesn't matter,
那大家再也沒有任何確定的事物了
then no one can be certain of anything,
而我浪費了我過去4...
and I've just wasted the last four --
不對 是過去16年的人生
no, 16 years of my life,
我畢業不畢業根本無所謂啊
and there's no point in me graduating!
我看得出來你非常不開心
Okay, I can tell that you're very upset,
你還可能因為期末考而累過頭
and you're probably really overtired from finals.
但如果你不去參加畢業典禮 會后悔一生
But you are gonna regret it if you don't go to graduation.
我跟你保證 無論你現在有什么煩心事
Look, I promise -- whatever is bothering you,
在典禮之后就會想通
figure it out after the ceremony --
-之后嗎 -是啊
- After?! - Yes.
有"之后"就意味著有"之前"
"After" implies "before"!
但如果1分鐘之前等于0分鐘之前
But if one minute ago is the same as zero minutes ago,
那之前就是現在 而現在就是之后
then before is now and now is after!
我通常聽到這種對白
Usually when I hear people talking like this,
都是在聽到別人點餐在催上菜的時候
we're walking through a Taco Bell drive-through.
親愛的 你有一半的人生都在被事物所震撼
Sweetie, half your life is having your mind blown.
我還記得我第一次聽到原來銀河系中的星星
I remember when I heard there were more stars in the galaxy
比一盒即時米飯里的米還多時的樣子
than grains of rice in a box of Uncle Ben's.
不是的 是宇宙中的星系總數
No, there are more galaxies
比世界上所有海灘中的沙加起來還多
than grains of sand on all the world's beaches.
我不能一下失去他們兩個
Okay, I can't lose 'em both!
-我來 艾麗克斯 -誰快來啊
- I got this! Alex... - Somebody?
"我一直不知何為真正的力量 直到..."
"I never knew true strength until --"
"我遇到一個沒有腳的人"
"I met a man with no feet."
等等 不是 這些卡沒按照順序擺
Wait. No. These cards are not in order.
等等 你們不許跟我搶
Wait. Nobody help her right now --
艾麗克斯 你是個聰明又自信的女孩
Alex, you're a smart, confident girl.
我知道你會做出正確的決定
I know that you're gonna make the right decision.
你剛把這表戴我手上了嗎
Did you just put this watch on me?
我有病得治啊
I have a problem.
我覺得如果艾麗克斯不想參加畢業典禮
I say if Alex doesn't want to go to her graduation,
那她自己決定了就好
that's her decision.
謝謝你 盧克
Thank you, Luke.
只要你知道
As long as you know
現在其實根本不是數學的問題就行
that whatever's going on here isn't about math.
我覺得你只是在害怕離開校園
Yeah, I think maybe you're afraid to leave school.
-什么 -你這輩子
- What? - Your whole life,
從小就知道你該做什么
you've always known exactly what you're supposed to do --
學習 得高分 反復
study, get good grades, repeat.
現在這要結束了 令你感到害怕
Now that's over, and it's scary.
有點像是0=1
Kind of like if zero equalled 1.
但你很幸運 你的傻子姐姐跟弟弟
But lucky for you, your dummy brother and sister
在現實社會中都摸爬滾打過了
have spent time in the real world.
如果我們都能站穩腳跟 你肯定沒問題
And if we can handle it, you're gonna do just fine.
真的嗎
You think?
相信我們
Trust us.
走啦 我們帶你去畢業典禮吧
Come on. Let's go get you graduated.
等等 那個門總卡住
Oh, hold on. That door gets jammed.
我得從里面打開
I have to open it from the inside.
我來開
I got it!
萊亨德·丹拿
Legend Danner.
致辭的事情我現在還是過不去
I still can't get over that commencement speech.
完全沒人笑啊
Not a single laugh.
我告訴你他沒發現什么元素吧 "笑"素
I'll tell you one element he didn't discover -- hilarium.
艾麗克斯·鄧菲
Alex Dunphy.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
我們也不想炫耀 但是...
We don't want to brag, but, uh...
是我們的孩子們促成的
Our kids did that.
是的
Yeah.
別 別又是手表啊
No! No more watches.
我什么時候買的這些啊
When did I order these ones?
媽 你猜怎么著
Hey mom, guess what?
怎么啦 小寶貝
What? Papi.
我朋友卡莉被踢出專業了
My friend Carly got cut from my program,
她老爸最近還剛給戲服部門捐錢呢
and her dad's funded our new costume department.
看來賄賂是沒用的
I guess bribes don't work.
全是憑我的本事
I got through all my merit.
-是啊 -這種時候就該獎賞自己
- Yeah!. - That calls for a reward.
這是什么
What is this?
曼尼 求你別告訴杰
Manny, please don't tell Jay.
燕麥葡萄干味啊 你知道嗎
Oatmeal raisin? You know what?
真正的藝術家不會阻止自己嘗試新體驗
A true artist doesn't close themselve off to new experiences.
哪怕是看起來再不妙的餅干...
Even vile illlevan cookies.
這就是我所選擇的人生道路
That's the path I've chosen.
盡量去體驗并觀察人事物
To experiences and observe everything
一起在這名為人生的美麗盛會上狂舞
in this beautiful pageant we called life.